Key Kiani

UX Designer

Dallas / TX

kevkiani.com

linkedin.com /in/kevkiani

214 995 4786

SKILLS

Illustrator Prototyping
Photoshop Wireframing
Sketch HTML / CSS
XD Balsamiq
Figma Research

CORE COMPETENCIES

Graphic Design

Typography Collaboration

Heuristic Evaluation

Web Design User Testing

Communication

Critical Thinking

Socratic Inquiry

INTERESTS

Design Screen Writing

Coffee ♥ Martial Arts

Keyboards Video Games

Sumo Wrestling Running
Bird Watching Comedy

Thriller Films

Passionate interdisciplinary, and user-experience designer with a compassion for learning and collaborating with his peers. Empathy-motivated and research driven, I strive to define the problems, establish its context, and then offer a solution. Understanding behaviours and the motivations creates the design in statistics and words— my goal is to reflect them into wireframes and prototypes. Ultimately, creating interesting and focused experiences for the user in mind.

EDUCATION

BA. Philosophy

University of North Texas 2017

UX Design Certification

Careerfoundry 2020

EXPERIENCE

Freelance

August 2013 - Present

Designed creative projects geared at advancing brand awareness in various industries for local businesses. Included work: Promotial print material, web assets, advertisements, stationary, brand guides, logos, and landing pages.

Alphagraphics

August 2019 - March 2020

Position: Design Specialist

Worked alongside high profile businesses such as Hyatt, Freedom Truck, Planned Parenthood, and North Texas Food Bank. Drove clients projects from the design stage and saw it to the end of print production. Made design decisions to optimize client's design to better suit their wanted outcome. Collaborated with design and production specialists to improve on print material, generating over \$100,000 for clientelle as a result.

Contango: The Stock Market Gaming App

February 2015 - February 2017

Position: Creative Director, Front-End Designer

Mobile app designed to streamline and socialize investing while introducing newcomers to the market. Led logo and brand design for iOS app from ideation to Apple App Store launch, including generation of all assets.

Designed digital advertisements used for social media campaigns that drove a 250% increase in app users. Worked with product and engineering teams throughout application buildout to implement designs into application.

CASE STUDIES

Dallas Nonprofit Design Jam 2020